根據真實故事改編
Based on a true story
托馬斯勳爵
Lord Thomas.
亨利勳爵
Lord Henry.
安布羅斯勳爵
Lord Ambrose.
羅伯特勳爵
Lord Robert.
沃爾特勳爵
Lord Walter.
你最好別令我失望 查爾斯·格雷
You'd better not let me down, Charles Grey.
我在你身上投了20幾尼的賭注呢
I've got 20 guineas riding on you.
才20?如果我是你 就會下雙倍
Only 20? I'd double that if I were you.
來吧 女士們
Come on, ladies.
奧爾索普莊園 1774年四月
Althorp Estate England, April 1774
先生 繞著跑道跑兩圈 聽我發令
Gentlemen, twice around the course, on my count.
三 二
Three, two,
一!
one!
快點 格雷先生!      快點 托馬斯!
Come on, Mr. Grey!        Come on, Thomas!
快點 格雷先生!      跑起來 沃爾特勳爵
Come on, Mr. Grey!        Run, Lord Walter!
快點 格雷先生!
Come on, Mr. Grey!
快點 格雷先生!你不會是累了吧
Come on, Mr. Grey. You're tired already.
快點 格雷先生!      快點!
Come on, Mr. Grey!        Faster!
公爵您一定覺得喬治亞娜很有魅力吧?
I trust Your Grace still finds Georgiana an attractive girl?
當然 斯賓塞夫人
Of course, Lady Spencer.
她是有教養的淑女
She's an accomplished lady of quality
恪盡職守
and devoted to her duties.
能說流利的法語 意大利語 拉丁語
She's fluent in French, Italian, Latin
精通騎術和舞蹈 還有...
and fully versed in horsemanship and dancing and...
是的 我看得出來 她是你的驕傲
Yes, I'm aware of all that. She's a credit to you.
我想不出任何理由阻礙
I can't think of anything that would stand in the way
締結如此美滿快樂的婚姻
of a singularly happy marriage.
這些事情並不是公爵所擔心的 斯賓塞夫人
These are not the issues that burden the Duke, Lady Spencer.
公爵所考慮的是繼承人的問題
It is His Grace's duty to produce an heir.
換而言之 當那一天到來的時候
On the other hand, your daughter may expect
你的女兒必定有可觀的回報
a handsome reward when that occurs.
謝謝 希頓      不用客氣
Thank you, Heaton.        Your Grace.
公爵您大可以放心
Your Grace may rest assured.
我們家族的女人
The women in our family
從未沒喪失過那方面的能力
have never forfeited on that account.
既然有此保證...
Well, with that assurance...
那就這樣吧
So be it, then.
快點 格雷先生!
Come on, Mr. Grey!
抱歉 女士們 但看來我的馬贏了
I do apologize, ladies, but it appears that my horse has won.
又擊敗我了 查爾斯
Beat me again, Charles.
做得很好 格雷先生      表現不錯
Well done, Mr. Grey.        Well done.
現在我們欠你多少呢?      你欠我40
So how much do we owe you?        You owe me 40.
20 40      我的報酬呢?
Twenty, 40.        My reward?
你想要什麼?
And what do you suggest?
您母親想見你 喬治亞娜小姐
Your mother wishes to see you, Lady Georgiana.
謝謝
Thank you.
非常抱歉 母親 我們是不是太吵鬧了?
I must apologize, Mama. Were we making too much noise?
不是 親愛的
Not at all, my darling.
我們有更重要的事要談 過來
We have more important things to talk of. Come here.
我聽到有傳聞      什麼?
I have heard a rumor.        Yes?
聽說再過不久 我的女兒
That I will soon be addressing my daughter
就能成為德文郡的公爵夫人
as Her Grace, the Duchess of Devonshire.
是真的嗎 母親?      是的
Is it true, Mama?        It is.
德文郡的公爵夫人?
The Duke of Devonshire?
我本想至少把你留到18歲
I had hoped not to part with you until 18 at the soonest,
但有此良緣
but, with such a fine match,
不放你走就顯得我太自私了
it would be selfish of me not to let you go.
他愛我?      是的 當然
He loves me?        Yes, of course.
我只見過他兩次
I have only met him twice.
當真心愛著一個人的時候
When one truly loves someone,
並不需要相交很深就能確定 喬治亞娜
one doesn't have to know them well to be sure, Georgiana.
馬上就能感受到
One feels it right away.
我相信你和他一起會很快樂
I do believe you will be happy with him.
我會的 母親 我知道我會的
I shall, Mama. I know I shall.
公爵夫人
快點!      她來了!
Come on!        She's here!
公爵夫人!公爵夫人!
Your Grace! Your Grace!
她來了!      公爵夫人!
There she is!        Duchess!
他們想要什麼?
What do they want?
當然是想見見我和我的新婚妻子
To see me and my new wife, of course.
是有點煩人 但你會習慣的
It can be a nuisance, but you'll get used to it.
倫敦 德文郡莊園
Devonshire House,London
歡迎您 公爵夫人
Welcome, Your Grace.
來 小傢伙 雨果 雨果 來
Come, boys. Come on. Hugo, Hugo. Come.
對 就這樣
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
好了 乖 乖 這邊走
It's all right. Yes, yes. This way.
雨果 來 小傢伙 過來
Hugo. Come, boy. Come.
剪刀 你們可以退下了
Scissors. You may go.
我無論如何也想不明白
For the life of me, I could never understand
為什麼女人的衣服要做得這麼複雜
why women's clothes must be so damn complicated.
我想這只是我們表現自己的方式而已
It's just our way of expressing ourselves, I suppose.
你的意思是什麼?
Whatever do you mean?
噯 你有這麼多方式表現自己
Well, you have so many ways of expressing yourselves,
然而 我們只能擺弄我們的帽子和裙子
whereas we must make do with our hats and our dresses.
你上床來好嗎?
Would you go to the bed?
人必須承擔自己的責任
One has to accept one's responsibility.
伴隨結婚而來的義務
Certain obligations come with marriage,
不管它們有多艱難
no matter how burdensome they may seem.
是的 但我們在一起的時候...
Yes, but when we are together...
我是說 當我們私下在一起的時候...
But when we are together, intimately, I mean...
我知道 那的確很煩人
I know. It can be a bother.
但是只要你能給他生個兒子
However, it is only until you have given him a son.
那樣的情況會減少 也不會那麼堅決
Then the occasions will become fewer and less determined.
我覺得只要他能不時跟我談談
I think it might feel different
感覺就會很不一樣
if he would talk to me every once in a while.
他並非不和藹 但他從來不和我交談
I mean, it's not that he's unkind, but he never talks to me.
我以為他就像父親那樣
I thought that he would be like Papa,
在冷酷的外表下
that under his cool reserve
有著深沉的情感
there'd be a wealth of depth and sentiment,
但除了他的狗 他對任何事情都不感興趣
but he isn't interested in anything, apart from his dogs.
喬 試著別對他太苛求
Try not to be too hard on His Grace, G.
他只不過在履行責任而已
He's merely intent on fulfilling his duty.
至於和他交談
And as for talking to him,
有什麼可以談論的呢?
well, whatever is there to talk about?
是的 你說得對
No, you're quite right.
居然覺得自己能和丈夫交談
How foolish of me to think that I should be able to
我真是太愚蠢了
converse with my husband.
喬治亞娜
Georgiana,
用耐心 堅毅和順從裝備自己
equip yourself with patience, fortitude and resignation.
兒子很快就會降生 到時你就會知道了
A boy will come soon enough, and then you'll see.
但是我們 輝格黨
But we, the Whig Party,
僅將這視作公平 正義及明智
simply see this as just, right and sensible.
將獨立帶給美洲
Just to bring independence to America.
爭取廢除奴隸買賣
Right to abolish the slave trade.
將自由帶給平民
And sensible to bring freedom to the common man,
這片受到賜福的土地 這個英國
so the blessings of this blessed plot, this England,
將會賜福居於此處的居民 令他們享有更多平等
may be more equally enjoyed by all of its inhabitants.
我要向我們的主人及恩人
I would like to propose a toast to our host and benefactor
公爵及其美麗的公爵夫人敬酒
His Grace the Duke and his beautiful new Duchess.
請起立
Please be upstanding.
敬公爵與公爵夫人!      敬公爵與公爵夫人！
The Duke and Duchess!        The Duke and Duchess!
真是出色的演講啊 福克斯先生
Excellent speech, Mr. Fox.
承蒙誇獎
I thank you.
向一群朋友演講總是比較容易的
It is always easier to address a congregation of friends,
尤其當那些朋友喝醉的時候
particularly when those friends are drunk.
公爵夫人對福克斯先生的演講有何看法呢?
And how did the Duchess find Mr. Fox's speech?
我得承認 政治演講令我感到不太自在
I must confess, I am not yet at ease with political speeches.
他們的形式妨礙我
Their very form tends to
看出他們的真正含義
obstruct my view of their actual meaning,
如若真有含義的話
if such there be.
演說的哪一部分
In which particular section of the speech
令你難以理解呢 夫人?
did the message elude Your Grace?
我同情你對大眾的感情
Well, I have great sympathy with your sentiments in general,
但我並不理解我們
but I fail to fully comprehend how far we,
也就是輝格黨
the Whig Party, that is,
離堅定實現自由有多遠
are fully committed to the concept of freedom.
我們想要擴大投票範圍      面向所有人?
We intend to extend the vote.        To all men?
天吶 當然不是
Heavens, no.
但肯定是面向更多人 適度自由
But certainly to more men. Freedom in moderation.
"適度自由"?
"Freedom in moderation"?
正是
Precisely.
我相信你是出於好心 福克斯先生
I'm sure you are full of the best intentions, Mr. Fox,
但我敢肯定 假如我能投票的話
but I dare say I would not spend my vote,
不會把自己的一票浪費在這麼含糊的陳述上
if I had it, of course, on so vague a statement.
一個宣稱自由 另一個不是
One is either free or one is not.
而自由的概念是絕對的
The concept of freedom is an absolute.
畢竟人不能適度死亡
After all, one cannot be moderately dead
或適度被愛 又或適度自由
or moderately loved or moderately free.
必須二擇其一
It must always remain a matter of either or.
我想說幾句話
I think it appropriate to say a few words.
當...
When...
你能否看一下房間
Could you check the chamber
看能不能找到      大人
and see if you can find...        Your Grace.
...別的法國緞帶?
...different kinds of French lace?
有什麼事嗎？      沒有
Is anything the matter?        No.
你剛剛離席了      是的 我已經吃完了
You just left.        Yes. Well, I had done eating,
而那些該死的演講令我煩心
and those damn speeches bore me to distraction.
我覺得以後應該禁止他們演講
I think we have to ban them in the future.
但你是輝格黨的主要支持者
But you are the Whigs' main supporter.
是的 我並不反感政治
Yes. Well, I've no problem with the politics.
我只是無法忍受誇誇其談
It's just the rhetoric I can't stand.
我應該和你一起去嗎?
Shall I come with you?
不 為什麼要跟我一起去?
No. I mean, why ever should you?
公爵大人很好 只是想休息一會而已
The Duke is perfectly well. He simply wanted to rest a while.
請坐 先生們
Do sit down, gentlemen.
是演講太長令公爵難以忍受嗎?
Was it the length of the speech that got the better of the Duke?
當然不是
Certainly not.
他非常喜歡
He enjoyed it immensely
還希望下次能說得再長一點
and expressed a hope that next time it would be even longer.
敬公爵夫人      敬福克斯先生
Your Grace.        Mr. Fox.
怎麼回事?      你無需過問
What's going on?        Nothing to concern you.
我不明白      過來
I don't understand.        Come here.
你今晚很美 這裙子是你設計的?
You look very beautiful tonight. Is this dress your design?
是的 謝謝誇獎
Yes, it is. Thank you.
那麼你應當樂意讓你的丈夫
Then I think you should allow your husband to appreciate it
欣賞更多細節
in a little more detail.
過來
Come here.
好 叫他們進來      我們有客人嗎?
Yes, send them in.        Are we having company?
你不覺得這羊肉嘗起來不太一樣嗎?
Don't you think this mutton has a funny taste?
不 不會      我覺得是
No. Not really, no.        I think it does.
喬 這位是夏洛特 她將和我們住在一起
G, this is Charlotte, and she will be staying with us.
為什麼?
Why?
因為她母親去世了 她沒別的地方可去
Because her mother is dead, and she has no other place to go.
那孩子是你的?
Have you fathered that child?
她...她不過是個小女孩 喬
It's... It's only a little girl, G.
這不是世界末日
It's hardly the end of the world.
你想讓我來照顧她?
Are you expecting me to look after her?
我們的房子有的是空房間
We have a house full of vacant rooms.
她不會麻煩你
She needn't bother you.
事實上 她會對你很有用處
In fact, she may even be of use to you.
你可以練習為人母親的技巧
You can practice your mothering skills,
直到我們的兒子出生為止
until our son arrives.
不 嘗起來不像正常的羊肉
No, this doesn't taste like normal mutton.
我覺得裡面肯定加了點東西
I'm sure there is something the matter with it.
拿走好嗎?
Could you take it away?
嘗起來像正常羊肉嗎?
Does it taste like normal mutton?
嘗起來像正常羊肉嗎?來
Does it taste like normal mutton? Come here.
就當它是正常羊肉吧 挑食的小傢伙
Think it tastes like normal mutton, fussy dog?
挑食的小狗狗
Who's a fussy mutton dog?
你的娃娃有名字嗎?
Does your doll have a name?
她一定很喜歡她的新睡房
l bet you she loves being in her new bedroom.
你給她取個名字 明天告訴我好嗎
You'll have to think of a name and let me know tomorrow.
能做到嗎?夏洛特
Do you think you'll be able to do that, Charlotte?
我...
l...
請讓我們單獨呆一會 好嗎?      是 夫人
Would you leave us, please?        Your Grace.
你好 夏洛特
Hello, Charlotte.
我叫喬治亞娜
My name is Georgiana.
晚上好      謝謝
Good evening.        Thank you.
晚上好 夫人
Good evening, ladies.
再大一英吋 夫人您就要分娩了
An inch more and I do believe Your Grace will explode.
謝裡登一向深諳恭維之道
Sheridan always knows how to pay a compliment.
還是得等上幾個星期
Still a few more weeks to wait.
無論是誰 挺著個大肚子都不會好看
A huge belly has never been more becoming on anyone.
福克斯在說經驗之談呢
Well, Fox, here, offers an expert opinion seeing,
每次經過鏡子旁邊 他都能看到自己的大肚子
as he does, a giant belly every time he passes a mirror.
如果你的大肚子是長在女人身上
If your belly were on a woman, well,
我們都知道是意味著什麼
we'd all know what to think.
親愛的謝裡登
My dear Sheridan,
一個小時前 我的大肚子壓是在一個女人身上
an hour ago my belly was on a woman.
現在你怎麼想?
Now what do you think?
這教訓你在賭局開始前
That will teach you to insult Mr. Fox
不要侮辱福克斯先生
before the gaming has begun.
很好
It's very good.
停止下注
No more bets, please.
夫人又贏了
Her Grace wins again.
再賭一把?
Another wager?
你沒事吧 夫人?      夫人!
Are you all right, Your Grace?        Your Grace!
那是陣痛嗎?我的妻子要分娩了
Are those labor pains? My wife is in labor.
快點
Come along.
我想這值得敬酒
I think this calls for a toast.
也許我的繼承人會在夜晚過去前降生
I may have an heir before the night is out.
女士們先生們 敬第六代德文郡公爵
Ladies and gentlemen, I give you the sixth Duke of Devonshire.
第六代德文郡公爵!
The sixth Duke of Devonshire!
大人
Your Grace.
我現在什麼都不想說
I am in no mood for a conversation.
但是 請務必告訴我 我的女兒是否...
But, pray tell me, is my daughter...
你的女兒是否能為我誕下麟兒?
Is your daughter at all able to give me a son?
放心吧 大人
Take heart, Your Grace.
只要母親健康
As long as the mother is in good health,
把這次不幸當作是草稿
consider this mishap a draft,
即將降臨的諾言
a promise of what is soon to come.
在我們的家族 我們...      是的 我知道 在你的家族裡
In our family, we...        Yes, I know, in your family,
在你的家族裡
in your family.
我先告退
Your Grace.
你看到這光芒嗎?看到嗎?
Can you see the light? Can you see it?
親愛的 你怎麼樣了?      我很好
Darling, how are you?        Quite well.
她是否健康強壯?      她很完美
Is she strong and healthy?        She's perfect.
威廉接待了你嗎?      是的
Did William receive you?        Yes.
他是否因她不是兒子而不高興?
Is he upset that she's not a son?
他看了她一眼就離開了
He just glanced at her and then left.
之後我就很少見到他了
I've hardly seen him since.
這段時期對公爵大人來說不好過 親愛的
It's been a difficult time for His Grace, my dear.
很多人在盯著他 而並非所有人都是友善的
Many eyes are upon him and not all of them kind.
她是個美女
She is the loveliest.
奶媽?      不 我親自哺育她
Nurse?        No, I will feed her.
你說真的嗎 親愛的?     是的
Are you sure, darling?        Yes.
畢竟我是她的母親 即使她是個女孩
I am her mother, after all, even if she is only a girl.
過來
There.
該死的!
Hell and damnation!
6年後
Six years later
夏洛特(右)
Charlotte
夏蘿(左)
Harryo
小喬治亞娜(中)
Little G
巴斯
The City of Bath
外出度假以尋求智慧之言
It is always a pleasure when one is on holiday
總是令人愉快的
to request a few words of wisdom.
不再贅言
And so without further ado,
我榮幸地請出
it is a great honor to hand over to
我們最高貴的來賓
our most distinguished guest.
當她出現 所有目光都凝注在她身上
When she arrives, all eyes are upon her.
當她離開 她是人們談論的對象
When absent, she is the subject of universal conversation.
她今晚所穿之物
And what we see her wearing tonight,
我期望明天看到你們都穿上!
I look forward to seeing the rest of you wearing tomorrow!
有請時尚女王 德文郡公爵夫人
The empress of fashion herself, the Duchess of Devonshire.
我們來巴斯是想擺脫倫敦
We come away to Bath to get away from London,
沒想到整個倫敦都來了巴斯
and all of London has come away to Bath.
的確有人問過我
Somebody did indeed ask me
我戴的是什麼羽毛
what kind of feather it is that I'm wearing.
這種稀有鳥類
Well, there are only two specimens
世上只剩兩隻
of this rare bird known to man.
其中一隻顯然在我頭上
One of them has clearly ended up on top of my head.
而另一隻
And the other,
據傳言是放在保守黨的辦公室裡
rumor has it, is running for office in the Tory Party.
貝絲·福斯特
Bess Foster.
失陪
Excuse me.
我們尚未互相介紹吧
I don't believe we've been introduced.
是的 我是伊麗莎白·福斯特夫人
No, we haven't. Lady Elizabeth Foster.
我看到你和我丈夫談話
I saw you talking with my husband.
是的 他想跳舞
Yes. He wanted to dance.
這通常不是他的長處 你婉謝了嗎?
That's not usually considered his forte. And you declined?
目前我並不想要任何異性的陪伴
I'm ill at ease with male company for the moment.
謝謝
Thank you.
那麼是什麼風把你吹來巴斯?
So what brings you to Bath?
我的丈夫福斯特先生
My husband, Mr. Foster,
正和情婦在伯恩茅斯風流快活
is enjoying his mistress in Bournemouth
我想找點消遣 你呢?
and I wanted some diversion. And you?
公爵是來浸浴治療痛風
The Duke is taking the waters for his gout.
而我是為了自己的健康      真的?
And I for my health.        Really?
我聽說你來這裡是因為生不出兒子
I heard you were here because you could not conceive a son.
請原諒 我不該說這樣的話
I beg your pardon, that was an awful thing to say.
至少說的是實話
It was the truth, at least.
我說了愚蠢的話 我一直都這樣
Trust me to say something silly. I always do, you know.
那麼也許你該接受公爵的邀請
Then perhaps you should have accepted the Duke's offer.
你們有很多共同點
You have much in common.
我想該回家了 喬治亞娜
Home, I think, Georgiana.
你住在哪裡呢?      我在鎮上租了幾個房間
Where are you staying?        I've rented some rooms in town.
我們一定要再見面      一定會的
We must meet again.        We must.
夏蘿 過來 過來 疼嗎?
Harryo. Come here. Come here. Did that hurt?
媽媽      我的小天使
Mama.        My angel.
你疼嗎?疼不疼?
Are you sore? Was that sore?
讓我看看 是膝蓋嗎?
Let me have a look. Was it this knee?
你會沒事的
I think you shall live.
好啦 衝到橋上去 我數三聲 一 二 三 跑
Right. First to the bridge on my count. One, two, three. Go.
快點啊 夏蘿
Come on, Harryo.
不 我會追上她的      我會追上你的!
No, I'm gonna catch her!        I'm gonna catch you!
跌倒了再爬起來
Up and down. Up and down.
為什麼我們不能像那樣重新開始呢?
Why can't we recover like that?
我們已長大成人了
It's too far to fall now.
又見面了 你好      你好 你的女兒很漂亮
Hello again.        Hello. Your girls are lovely.
謝謝 你有孩子嗎?      我有 三個男孩
Thank you. Do you have any children?        I do. Three boys.
三個男孩
Three boys.
哪怕能得到一個 公爵就已經願意捨棄一切了
What the Duke wouldn't give for one of them.
年紀最大的那個長得最不像你
She is least like you, your eldest.
是的 我想你都聽說了吧
Yes. I'm sure you know the story.
在我們結婚之前 我丈夫的女兒已經出生
My husband's daughter was born before we married.
她的母親是個女僕 女僕死後我們接收了那個孩子
Her mother was a maid. The maid died, and we took the child.
抱歉 我是不是說得太多了?      不是
I'm sorry. Have I spoken out of turn?        No.
這在倫敦已是公開的秘密了
It's the worst kept secret in London.
她現在已經九歲了
She's nine years old now.
你愛她?
And you love her?
當然 就像自己親生的一樣
Of course I do. The same as all my children.
過來見見他們
Come and meet them.
姑娘們 過來見見我的新朋友 伊麗莎白夫人
Girls. Come and meet my new friend, Lady Elizabeth.
夫人      謝謝 溫泉水
Your Grace.        Thank you. Thermal water.
那股味道是硫帶來的
It's the sulfur that makes it smell so bad.
你真的要喝這個嗎?
And you really have to drink it?
一天兩次 喝一個月
Twice a day for four weeks.
你知不知道自己為什麼生不出男孩呢?
Do you have any reason to believe you cannot birth a male?
不 除了流產
No. Except miscarriages.
兩次產下死胎 都是男胎
Two stillbirths, both sons.
但能生下兩個健康的女孩
But two healthy girls.
每個人都在盯著你
Everybody is staring at you.
你脖子上的是什麼?貝絲
What's that on your neck? Bess?
用棍毆打妻子並不犯法
It's not illegal for a man to beat his wife with a stick
除非棍子比他的拇指還厚
unless the stick is thicker than his thumb.
福斯特先生?但他不可能做這樣的事!
Mr. Foster? But he can't have done that!
想想他對我做過的其他事
Well, considering what else he's done to me,
這已經不是最糟的
that's not the worst.
還有什麼更糟的?
What could possibly be worse?
他奪走我的孩子 不讓我見他們
He's taken my children. He won't let me see them.
你打算怎麼辦呢?
And what do you propose to do?
我真的無計可施了
Really, I'm at my wits' end.
法律站在福斯特先生那邊
The law supports Mr. Foster.
那這段時間你住在哪裡呢?
In the meantime, where shall you stay?
繼續租住 直到錢用盡為止
Continue lodging, till the money runs out.
至少這一點我能幫得上忙
Well, there, at least, I think I can help.
威廉?我們明天就離開
William? We leave tomorrow.
伊麗莎白夫人起碼有一段時間
And Lady Elizabeth doesn't have to meet her parents
不需要去內陸看父母
on the continent for some time.
她都沒怎麼參觀過倫敦呢
She hardly ever visits London at all.
真遺憾啊
It's a pity, that.
你瞧 她沒別的地方可以呆了
You see, she doesn't have anywhere to stay.
那是個問題
Problem there.
那麼她為什麼不和我們住在一起呢?
Well, why doesn't she stay with us?
至少呆上一段時間
For a while, at least.
謝謝
Thank you.
真不可思議啊      在愛爾蘭有城堡
This is incredible.        There's the castle in lreland.
博爾頓修道院 齊斯克之屋 百靈頓大屋
Bolton Abbey, Chiswick, Burlington and,
當然還有察茲沃斯宮
why, in Chatsworth, of course.
當然      那更大了
Of course.        Which is much bigger.
但這裡更像一個家
But this is more like home.
很高興你在這裡
I'm so glad you're here.
我為這個季度安排了一個精彩的起點
I've arranged a wonderful start to the season.
如果我再和你做朋友
May all the plagues of marriage be doubled on me
就讓我加倍承受婚姻的折磨吧
if ever I try to be friends with you anymore!
那就更好了
So much the better.
不 不 夫人 顯然你一點也不在乎我!
No, no, madam. 'Tis evident you care not a pin for me!
娶你這樣的人 我真是發瘋了
And I, I was a madman to marry you.
嫁給你這樣的人 我真是蠢極了
And I'm sure I was a fool to marry you,
搖搖欲跌的單身老漢
an old dangling bachelor
單身到五十歲
who was single at 50
只因從來沒有人看上他!
only because he never could meet with anyone who could have him!
貝絲 請容許我介紹福克斯先生 反對派的領袖
Bess, may I introduce Mr. Fox, leader of the Opposition?
福克斯先生 這位是伊麗莎白·福斯特夫人      福克斯先生
Mr. Fox, Lady Elizabeth Foster.        Mr. Fox.
我的門生 查爾斯·格雷      格雷先生
My protege, Charles Grey.        Mr. Grey.
格雷先生      夫人
Mr. Grey.        Your Grace.
他是我們的新進英才
He's our newest bright young man.
剛從劍橋畢業不久 就已經位列議會
Scarcely out of Cambridge and already a member of Parliament.
我一直覺得你很出色      謝謝
I always felt you'd do well.        Thank you.
福克斯先生      伊麗莎白夫人
Mr. Fox.        Yes, Lady Elizabeth.
你喜歡這個戲劇嗎?
Did you enjoy the play?
我得老實承認 並不太喜歡
I must confess, I did not entirely.
希望你進入政界之後
I hope that you've not lost your sense of humor
沒有喪失幽默感      我並不擔心這個
since entering politics.        Not that I'm aware.
那麼你想必意識到《造謠學校》（英國古典派喜劇）
Then I'm sure you realize that School for Scandal
是被當作喜劇來描寫      是的
was written as a comedy.        Yes.
儘管從我的角度看來 它更像是悲劇
Although, from where I sat, it read as a tragedy.
夫人!我們多想念你啊
Your Grace! How we have missed you.
缺了你
In your absence,
倫敦變得沉悶不堪
London has been reduced to the dreariest province.
這位是劇作家謝裡丹先生
And this, of course, is the playwright Mr. Sheridan.
請容許我介紹伊麗莎白·福斯特夫人
May I present the Lady Elizabeth Foster?
我並非有意打擾
I do not mean to be rude,
但我的所有演員都極想覲見公爵夫人
but I've an entire cast dying to meet the Duchess.
一會就把你送回來 我保證
I shall return you in a moment. Promise.
福克斯先生?      嗯?
Mr. Fox?        Yes.
借一步說話
A word.
我在哪裡發掘國內醜聞的題材呢?
Well, wherever do I glean such domestic gossip?
這樣對公爵大人公平嗎?
Were we fair on the Duke?
本來還可以更糟糕的
It could have been worse.
我原定的劇名是《糟糕的婚姻》
My original title was The Bad Marriage.
情況真的是這樣的嗎?
Is it always like this?
噯 正如他們所說
Well, as they say,
德文郡公爵是全英國唯一
the Duke of Devonshire must be the only man in England
不愛慕他妻子的人
not in love with his wife.
這位是德文郡公爵夫人
Her Grace, the Duchess of Devonshire.
很榮幸見到您
Very pleased to meet you.
你已拋開那一切 玩得開心嗎?
Were you at all able to forget things and enjoy yourself?
這是很好的娛樂 謝謝
It was a wonderful distraction, thank you.
很好
Good.
我一整晚都在和格雷先生交談      是嗎?
I talked to Mr. Grey all evening.        Yes?
他愛上你了
He's in love with you.
親愛的貝絲 不 他不是的 恐怕剛好相反
My dear Bess, no, he is not. Quite the reverse, I fear.
你難道感覺不到他凝視你的眼神嗎?
Well, can't you tell by the way he looks at you?
說真的 你真的感覺不到嗎?      別說了
Honestly, can't you tell?        Stop it.
喬治亞娜 交合併不只是為了後嗣
Georgiana, intercourse is not just about offspring.
事實上 是可以很愉悅的      我知道
In fact, it can be rather pleasurable.        Yes, I know.
閉上眼睛想像一下
Close your eyes and try to envisage Grey
格雷先生掀開你的裙子 親吻你的後背
opening your dress, kissing your back.
他們不會做那樣的事      會的 他們會
They never do such things.        Yes, they do.
閉上你的眼睛
Close your eyes.
格雷在你背後慢慢的打開你的裙子
Grey is behind you slowly opening your dress.
不 貝絲 別說了!      閉上眼
No, Bess, stop!        Close your eyes.
親吻你的後背
Kissing your back.
那裡
There.
明白了吧?
See?
失陪一下
Would you excuse me for a minute?
夫人      格雷先生
Your Grace.        Mr. Grey.
選舉在六星期後舉行 是吧?
The national election is in six weeks, yes?
競選進行得怎樣了?
How is the campaign going?
很糟糕
Terribly.
我們唯一的希望的是為福克斯保住威斯敏斯特
Our only hope is to save Westminster for Fox.
正如你所知 我有很多毛病
I have many faults, as you well know.
其中包括善於吸引別人的目光
Not least among them is my ability to draw attention.
也許我們可以利用那點作為我們的優勢
Perhaps we could use that to our advantage.
女士們先生們
Ladies and gentlemen.
Ladies and gentlemen,
我向你們介紹 指引我們該做何事
I give you the man who will inform us of the work we must do
該信何黨派的人 查爾斯·格雷先生
and of the party we so believe in. Mr. Charles Grey.
威斯敏斯特的人們!
Good people of Westminster!
世界正面臨崩潰或得救的邊緣
The world is on the brink of disaster or salvation!
從法國到美洲
From France to America,
男人和女人都在為自己的自由而奮鬥
men and women are struggling to free themselves,
尋找自我存在的價值!
to find meaning in their existence!
變革就在我們眼前!
Change is upon us!
我們不應倒退回舊日
We shall not go back to the old ways.
應當把英國帶進勇敢的新時代
We shall take England into this brave new world
撼動天空!
and shake the thunder from the skies!
我表現得怎樣?      我覺得你並不困窘
How did I do?        I think it was not an embarrassment.
真是奇跡
It was a marvel.
我很緊張 你的到場令我的緊張放大了三倍
I was nervous. Your presence trebled the numbers at least.
即使現在 我仍然緊張
I'm nervous even now.
假如我能贏得選舉 假如我得到權力
If we win this election, if we get the power,
想想我們能做什麼
think what we will do.
我們分開的時候 你有想我嗎?
Do you think of me when we're not together?
你知道我有的
You ought to know I do.
在回答之前 你猶豫了      不
You hesitated before you replied.        No.
從來沒有人這麼直接問我
I'm unused to being asked so directly.
無論是你還是其他人
And by you, of all people.
我一直在想著你 無時無刻都想
I think of you all the time. I always have.
您的馬車在等著呢 夫人      謝謝
Your carriage awaits, Your Grace.        Thank you.
...我們就此立誓
...this we vow!
你們在伊麗莎白夫人的房間外面做什麼?
What are you doing outside Lady Elizabeth's room?
誰和她在裡面?
Who's in there with her?
英國有那麼多女人 你偏偏要纏上她
Of all the women in England you had to throw yourself on her.
我從未拒絕過你任何事
I have never once objected to any of your affairs.
我接受所有你作出的安排
I have accepted whatever arrangement you have proposed.
我將夏洛特視為己出
I have raised Charlotte as my own daughter.
但這個...
But this...
這是我唯一僅剩的
I have one single thing of my own.
你為什麼不能把伊麗莎白留給我?
Why couldn't you let me keep Elizabeth for myself?
你到底是什麼人啊?
What kind of man are you?
在我們的婚姻生活裡 她是唯一能給我慰藉的
She is my sole comfort in our marriage.
你搶走了我唯一的朋友!
You have robbed me of my only friend!
我犯了什麼錯?
What is wrong with me?
我...
l...
我沒說過我是感性的人 喬
I've never claimed to be a man of fine sensibility, G.
但我很清楚自己想從這段婚姻中得到什麼
But I've always known what I expect from this marriage
和付出什麼
and what I'm prepared to give.
作為丈夫 我履行了自己的義務
As a husband, I have fulfilled my obligations.
但作為妻子
But, as a wife,
你沒有
you have not.
她要離開 馬上就走
She has to go. Now.
再也不能踏入這房子半步!
She is never to set foot in this house again!
喬 控制一下自己的脾氣 你太失禮了
Do mind your temper, G. You're forgetting yourself.
我要她走
I want her out.
我再也不想見到她
I never want to lay eyes on her again.
下去叫她馬上走
Go down and tell her to leave at once.
我不能要她那麼做
I couldn't ask her that.
我不會那樣做 喬
I won't do it, G.
從一開始我就不喜歡她
I never liked her from the first.
你說得很清楚了 母親
You made that quite clear, Mama.
但願她已經離開了德文郡莊園
She's gone from Devonshire House, I hope.
他們一起住在那裡?
They're living there together?
喬治亞娜!你居然容忍這樣的事?
Georgiana! What have you permitted to happen?
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
幫我 幫幫我 求你了 母親 告訴我該怎麼辦
Help me. Help me, please, Mama. Tell me what to do.
你得寫信給丈夫 堅持要求送走她
You must write to your husband and insist he send her back
回她原來呆的糟糕地方
to whatever horrid little place she came from.
他不會的 他說"這是不可能的"
He will not. ''It is out of the question,'' he says.
那麼你要回去 履行為人妻子的義務
Then you must return and resume your duties.
讓她知道他真正愛的人是誰
Make him realize whom he loves.
你要放棄政治生活和賭博
You will give up your politics and your gambling.
這次 你要全心全意做個好妻子
For once, you will devote yourself as a loving wife
親手解決問題 給他生一個繼承人
and settle down to the task in hand, providing him with an heir.
那麼他很快就會厭倦她
Then he will soon tire of her.
你沒有其他選擇
You have no other option.
你好 喬
Hello, G.
威廉
William.
我也許無權將你趕出房子
I may not have the authority to remove you from my house,
但我至少可以命令你離開我的房間
but I can, at least, order you out of my room.
你就不能聽我解釋嗎?
Won't you please let me explain?
沒什麼好解釋的
There is nothing to explain.
這是我見孩子們的唯一機會
This is my only chance of ever seeing my children again.
公爵是英國最有權勢的貴族
The Duke is the most powerful peer in England.
他是我唯一的機會
He is my only chance.
即使是為了孩子 犧牲也是有個限度的
There are limits to the sacrifices one makes for one's children.
不 不是的 犧牲一切也不為過
No, there aren't. No limits whatsoever.
出去
Get out.
我們之間沒什麼好說的
We have nothing more to say to one another.
媽媽 媽媽
Mama, Mama!
見到你真好 媽媽
It's so nice to see you, Mama.
是的 這是獵槍
Right, this is a shotgun.
你母親說你會感興趣的 對嗎?
Your mother said you'd be interested, yes?
是的
Yes.
這是打火石 你看到了嗎?
This is a flint. Do you see?
當打火石撞到這裡 就會產生火花
When the flint hits there, it causes a spark to happen.
火花點燃火藥
Now, the spark, it lights the gunpowder
把子彈推出槍外
and sends the bullet out of the gun.
你知道怎麼拿槍嗎?      不知道 先生
Do you know how to hold it?        No, sir.
是這樣的
Well, it's like that.
夾在右邊腋窩下
Tuck it in there,into your right shoulder.
緊緊的托住
Hold it firmly,
那隻手可以再挪遠一點
then you can move that hand a little further along.
你感受到它的重量了吧?要再往前傾一點
Can you feel how heavy it is? You have to lean into it a bit.
兩隻眼睛保持睜開 順著槍管看過去
And keep both eyes open. Look right along the barrel.
就是這樣
Right along there just like that.
砰!來 我做給你看看
Bang! Here, let me show you.
那裡
There.
很沉 是吧?
It's quite heavy, isn't it?
你口渴嗎?要不要喝點什麼?
Are you thirsty? Would you like something to drink?
你們口渴嗎?要喝點什麼嗎?
Are you gentlemen thirsty? Would you like something to drink?
謝謝
Thank you.
你有沒有告訴公爵要見什麼人呢?
Did you tell the Duke who you were meeting?
沒有
No.
那他問了嗎?      沒有
Did he even ask?        No.
他還有別的事情要想
He has other things on his mind.
你也一樣
As do you.
你要是說出來會不會好一點?
Would it help to unburden yourself?
我不能跟你討論那些事
It's nothing I can discuss with you.
就算說了也徒增煩惱而已
Besides, it would only bore.
你不需要總是取悅別人
You don't have to please others all the time.
我從小的教育就是這樣
It's what I've been brought up to do.
想改掉還挺困難的
Difficult lesson to unlearn.
我可否發表一個見解?
Would you permit me an observation?
我認為你這麼做是為了讓人們喜歡你
I believe you do it so that people will love you.
你憑什麼這麼說?      憑我所看到的
What makes you say that?        From what I've seen.
從你的丈夫 你的朋友 尤其是貝絲夫人
With your husband, your friends, especially Lady Bess,
甚至是其他公眾
even the public.
我以前還從來沒這麼想過
I never thought of it that way before.
你說得我好像很可憐
You make me sound so pitiable.
喬治安娜
Georgiana.
我說過頭了 我向你道歉
I've gone beyond my brief. I apologize.
請相信我這麼說是為你好
Please believe it was only for your sake that I spoke.
請告訴我到底出什麼事了
Please, tell me what is wrong.
我想我的一生裡有些事情做得太晚
I fear I've done some things in life too late
有些做得太早
and others too early.
不 你沒有
No, you haven't.
對不起
I'm sorry.
謝謝
Thank you.
好了
All right.
好了?
''All right''?
你們兩情相悅嗎?
Do you love each other?
喬治安娜      你喜歡貝絲嗎? 大人
Georgiana...        Do you love Bess, Your Grace?
這是幹什麼?      我對他別無所求
Where is all this leading?        I make no demands on him.
貝絲 你喜歡我丈夫嗎?
And, Bess, do you love my husband?
跟我對你是一樣的
As I do you.
所以你打算留下來?
And so you intend to stay?
威廉叫我留下來
William has asked that I do.
你從心底無法拒絕他吧?
You couldn't find it in your heart to refuse him?
是的
No.
那我們定個協議吧
Then let us make a deal.
協議?      是的
A deal?        Yes.
我願意成全你們
I give you my blessing
如果你可以接受我對查爾斯·格雷的感情
if you will accept my feelings for Charles Grey.
我起初沒有意識到
I didn't realize it at first.
我以為那也許只是一種調情
I thought that perhaps it was only a dalliance.
它讓我感到快樂
It can make me happy.
協議? 協議
A deal? A deal.
我不跟人定協議
I don't make deals.
為什麼要呢?
Why would l?
一切都是由我在主宰
I'm in charge of it all.
我可以找他出來 我可以挑戰他
You know, I would call him out. I would challenge him.
我可以一槍打爆他的頭      威廉
I'd put a bullet in his head.        William.
安靜些
Be quiet.
你是決心要讓我淪為大笑柄嗎?
Are you determined to make me a total laughingstock?
一個無法生兒子的人 一個戴綠帽的人?
A man who cannot sire a son, and then a cuckold?
威廉 喬治安娜只是說我們...
William. Georgiana only asks what we ourselves...
安靜些! 你這女人!
Be quiet, woman!
你是他的婊子嗎?      不是
Are you his whore?        No.
但我不知道你為什麼要介意
But I can't see why you'd mind.
你有貝絲 還有三個兒子      三個兒子?
You have Bess and three boys!        Three boys?
你覺得我會讓那些雜種做我的繼承人嗎?
Do you think I can make those bastards my heirs?
是嗎 你這樣認為?
Well? Do you?
威廉!
William!
你一點也不瞭解我 是吧?
You don't know me in the least, do you?
不 我知道我們是很不合適的一對
Yes, I do. We're a bad match.
當我們結婚時 我要的是兩件事 忠誠和兒子
I asked but two things when we wed, loyalty and a male heir.
跟你對狗的要求一樣
The same as your dogs!
不 別碰我 別碰我
No, don't touch me! Don't touch me!
放開我
Get off!
Get off me!
你對她也是這樣嗎?你對那個賤人也是這樣嗎?
Is this how you treat her? Is this how you treat your whore?
不! 不!
No! No!
不! 不! 不!
No! No! No!
不!
No!
跟我來 夏洛特 跟我來
Come with me. Charlotte, come with me.
不! 不!
No! No!
給我生個兒子
Give me a son.
在那之前 好好呆著 老實聽我的話
Until then, stay here and do as I say.
勝出者是福克斯先生! 人民的選擇!
I give you the winner. Mr. Fox, the man of the people!
請容許我隆重介紹德文郡的公爵夫人
And I give you the weapon, the Duchess of Devonshire.
謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝你們 謝謝各位參加今天的招待會
Thank you, all of you, for this reception today.
今天我們贏得了選舉 明天我們要構建未來
Today we have won the vote. Tomorrow we define the future!
公爵     公爵
Your Grace.        Your Grace.
公爵      公爵
公爵
Your Grace.
公爵      公爵
Your Grace.        Your Grace.
公爵夫人 能否請您跳支舞?
Will Your Grace give me the favor of a dance?
站穩點 喬
Steady, G.
著火了!      喬治安娜!
Fire!        Georgiana!
夫人!
Your Grace!
夫人的頭髮!
Her Grace's hair!
想想辦法啊!
Do something!
請把夫人頭髮上的火滅掉
Please put out Her Grace's hair.
夫人需要休息
Her Grace needs to rest.
只要她謹遵醫囑
As long as she follows strict instructions
生產就不應該會有問題
there should be no impediment to the birth.
你說什麼?
What are you talking about?
公爵夫人有孕了
The Duchess is pregnant.
德文郡
Devonshire
還有這裡
And there.
謝謝你 希頓
Thank you, Heaton.
進來
Come.
夫人
Your Grace.
按照公爵大人的繼承權條約 這是給你的
As per the terms of His Grace's inheritance, this is for you
任你支配
to spend as you wish.
終於成功了
Success at last.
喬治安娜
Georgiana.
我對此也深感痛恨
I, too, abhor this whole thing.
換還是不換?
Twist or stick?
不換      不換?
Stick.        Stick?
那我也不換了
I'll stick, too, then.
翻開看看
Let's see.
你贏了 真厲害
You won. Well done.
媽媽 你忘了發牌了
Mama, you forgot to deal.
夫人      格雷先生
Your Grace.        Mr. Grey.
你從法國被召回了?      暫時的
You are recalled from France?        For a while.
還沒有革命嗎?
No revolution yet?
還沒有 不過是遲早的事
No, not yet, but it's only a matter of time.
你怎麼會來這裡?      我接到一個請柬
How is it you are here?        I received an invitation.
我以為那是黨派的邀請 不能拒絕
I assumed it was on behalf of the Party. I could not say no.
那是自然
Of course.
我生了個兒子
I bore a son.
是嗎
Yes.
他叫威廉·喬治·斯賓塞·卡文迪什
His name is William George Spencer Cavendish,
哈廷頓侯爵
Marquis of Hartington.
我們叫他哈特
We call him Hart.
你和公爵一定都很高興吧
You and the Duke must be very pleased.
是的
We are.
公爵到倫敦慶祝去了
The Duke has gone to London to celebrate.
我想你
You have been missed.
很想你
Much missed.
Q押5
Queen on five.
請停止下注
And no more bets, please.
輸牌是 4
The losing card, four.
贏牌是 Q
The winning card, Queen.
好極了 八押3
Jolly good. Eight on the three.
在5上押五
Put five on the five.
5都已經沒了 喬
All of the fives have gone, G.
我累得不想再玩了
I think I'm too tired to play.
先生們 失陪了     夫人
Gentlemen.        Your Grace.
喬治安娜
Georgiana.
不可讓任何人知道
No one must know.
是你召回格雷的?     晚安
You summoned Grey.        Good night.
我打算去巴斯
I was thinking about going to Bath.
貝絲 我去休養時
Bess, you can stay here
你可以留下來照顧我們的丈夫
and look after our husband whilst I take the cure.
是呀 威廉 為什麼不呢?
Yes, William. Why not?
如果她現在去了 在你有空時我們可以去找她
If G goes now, we can catch up with her when you're free.
好吧 如果你一定要去
Well, if you must.
"德文郡的公爵夫人"
"The Duchess of Devonshire "
"上周戴著室內帽出現在巴斯"
"appeared last week in Bath in a mobcap."
"自從公爵夫人"
"Her Grace,"
"被邀請參與選舉活動以來"
ever since initiation into the business of electioneering,"
"她就跟公眾走得很近"
"has been much attached to the mobs."
非常好
Very good.
你最喜歡哪一個
So which one is your favorite?
這一個      是呀
This one.        Yeah.
這張好像是你難得一次連贏幾把
In this one it seems you've hit a winning streak, for once.
非常好
Very good.
而這一張...
And in this one you see...
穿這身衣服去吸引投票者合適嗎?
Is that dress really an appropriate way to attract voters?
你們政治家對服裝真是一無所知
You politicians know absolutely nothing about fashion.
如果你真的問我最喜歡哪一個
But if you were to really ask me which my favorite was,
我會說是這一個
I'd say it was this one.
早上好 查爾斯      早上好
Morning, Charles.        Morning.
你好 先生
Good day to you, sir.
非常好 謝謝
It's perfect. Thank you.
還以為會給你一個驚喜呢 喬
Thought we would surprise you, G.
我記得你說過我們的婚姻生活裡
I think you once said there wasn't enough spontaneity
欠缺一些主動
in our marriage
或是類似的話
or words to that effect.
母親 你怎麼會來這裡
Mama, what are you doing here?
你見過我們在巴斯的一些朋友嗎?
So, have you seen many of our circle in Bath?
見過一些
Some.
科克斯一家還有哈弗福德和威克洛男爵
The Cokes and Haverford and Lord Wicklow.
還有一些政治家是吧 一些會議什麼的
Bunch of politicos, too, aren't there? Meetings and such.
我想是吧
I believe.
格雷在這裡嗎? 我是說查爾斯·格雷
Is Grey here? By which I mean Mr. Charles Grey.
有傳聞說他在這裡
Rumor has it that he is.
我不會放棄他的     喬治安娜
I won't give him up.        Georgiana.
每個人都有一個心愛的人 貝絲是我丈夫的愛人
Everyone has a lover. Bess is the lover of my husband.
如果你有任何的判斷能力
If you had shown some discretion,
事情可能會更得很不同     很不同?
it might have been different.        Different?
唯一幸運的是這一切還沒上過報紙
The only good fortune is it hasn't yet made it to the papers.
親愛的 格雷獨身 他沒有財產 沒有官爵
My dear, Grey is unmarried. He has no wealth, no rank.
這件事他無需擔任何風險 你將承受所有傷害
He risks nothing with this affair. The hazard is all yours.
格雷是愛我的     威廉也一樣
Grey loves me.        So does William.
是的 我愛你
Yes. I love you.
怎麼愛?
How?
以我所理解的愛的方式
In the way I understand love.
喬治安娜 這事做得太過頭了
Georgiana, this has gone much too far.
有失我們的身份
It is beneath our dignity.
整個倫敦都在談論     讓他們說吧
All London is talking.        Let them talk.
如果格雷令我淪為墮落的女人 我不介意
If Grey makes me a fallen woman, well and good.
威廉可以跟我離婚
Now William may divorce me
讓貝絲成為德文郡公爵夫人
and Bess becomes Duchess of Devonshire.
這是不可能的
That will never happen.
我不管了
I think I will leave you to it.
現在要怎麼樣呢
What follows now?
你要撕開我的衣服
Are you going to tear my clothes off
再次對我用強嗎?
and force yourself upon me again?
我為什麼要這麼做?
Why on earth would I do that?
我知道你從未思考過
I know that you've never thought much of
我的才智和行事方式 喬
my manners or my intellect, G.
但事實上 我從不做沒用的事
But, in fact, I never do anything that serves no purpose.
我完全清楚你們為什麼在一起
I know precisely what you two have together.
我們彼此相愛     我毫不懷疑
We love each other.        I do not doubt it.
他跟你一樣是個理想主義者
He is a dreamer like yourself,
你們都在夢想一個
and you both dream of another world
不曾也將不會存在的世界
that does not exist and it never will.
在現實中呢 讓我給你點啟示
As for reality, allow me to enlighten you.
如果你不立即與他斷絕關係
If you do not give him up at once,
我會調查整個國家
I will see to it that every home
與他關聯所有家庭和賬本
and every checkbook in this country is closed to him.
他將會為所有的政府部門
He will be welcomed neither in the halls of government
和權力機構所拒絕
nor in its backrooms of power.
他想成為首相的夢想
His dream of becoming prime minister
還有你們想要改變世界的幻想都將化為灰燼
and your mutual fantasy of a changed world will be dead as ash.
而你也將永遠看不到你的孩子
And you will never see your children again.
喬治安娜
Georgiana.
我要請你回倫敦去
I must ask you to return to London.
你不去?     是的
Without you?        Yes.
這是我們的女兒讓我帶的
These are from our girls.
小哈特沒有寫
Little Hart neglected to write,
他太小也寫不了
but then, of course, he's not yet one.
這將是你一生中最大的錯誤     不
This will be the mistake of your life.        No.
很多年前我已經犯過那個錯了
I made that many years ago.
我想你自己可以離開吧
I trust you can see yourself out.
該死的 打門打開       是的 大人
Damn you, man, open the door!        Your Grace.
媽媽 媽媽 媽媽 媽媽
Mama, Mama, Mama, Mama!
媽媽 媽媽 媽媽
Mama, Mama, Mama.
去吧 孩子們     媽媽 我愛你
Come on, girls.        Mama. I love you.
孩子們 去吧 媽媽一會兒就來
Girls, run along. Your mother will join you in a minute.
來吧
Come on.
去吧
Run along.
喬
G.
你知道我很高興
You must know how greatly pleased I am
我們終於能夠達成妥協
that we have come to an arrangement.
讓孩子們離開母親太久
It's not good for little ones to
不是件好事
be without their mother for so long.
我的人生是為了他們     這是一種理解方式
My life for theirs.        That's one way of putting it.
你母親稱之為
Your mother called it
"眾人尊嚴高於個人欲求"
"common decency before personal gratification,"
或者是類似的話 具體我不記得
or some such thing. The exact words escape me.
不如說"被囚困在自己的家中"
How about "imprisoned in my own house"?
不 她不是這麼說的
No. That's not how she put it.
否則我會記得
I would have remembered that.
喬治安娜!
Georgiana!
放開我!
Unhand me!
喬治安娜!
Georgiana!
喬治安娜! 請放開我!
Georgiana! Will you please unhand me?
失陪一下
Excuse me.
喬治安娜! 放開
Georgiana! Please.
喬治安娜!
Georgiana!
謝謝你 伯利     放開他
Thank you, Burleigh.        Let him go.
我每天寄出十幾封信
I have written a dozen times a day.
可沒有你的任何回音
Still, there is nothing from you.
到底怎麼回事? 你不再愛我了嗎?
What has happened? Do you love me no longer?
我的個人感覺從未改變
My personal feelings remain unaltered.
那我們就應該在一起
Then we must be together again.
我想娶你 我想與你生兒育女
I want to marry you. I want you to bear my children.
而我才不在乎是男孩還是女孩!
And I don't care if they're boys or girls!
我也希望能夠這樣    可以的 會的
I wish it could be that way.        It can. It will.
無論我們如何躲避 悲傷總是難免的
Sorrows will come however we try to avoid them.
我們必須堅持到底 永不放棄
We must stay the course and never give in.
不 查爾斯      你必須要跟我離開
No, Charles.        You must leave and be with me.
做一個自由的女人 走吧 我們現在就走
A free woman. Now! Let us leave now!
我不能丟下我的孩子
I cannot abandon my children.
好好想想你要我做的是什麼吧
Listen to what you are asking me to do.
怎麼了? 不喜歡吃鴿子嗎?
What's the matter? Don't like the pigeon?
我覺得挺好吃的
I find it quite decent.
我懷了查爾斯·格雷的孩子
I'm carrying Charles Grey's child.
請幫我向公爵夫人轉達我的決定
Please be so kind as to inform the Duchess of my decision.
事情的安排是這樣的
This is how it will be.
你會被送到鄉下
You will be taken to the country
把孩子生下來
where you will give birth to the child,
那孩子將會由查爾斯·格雷的家庭
and the child will be trusted to the care
撫養成人
of Charles Grey's family.
你在聽嗎?
Are you listening?
我想她聽到了 我們走吧
I think she's heard you. Let's leave her.
喬治安娜 拜託     我說我們走了
Georgiana, please.        I said let's leave.
這不是在討論問題 她已經聽到我的決定了
This is not a discussion. She's been informed of my decision.
對她有點同情心吧 威廉     同情什麼
Have pity on her, William.        Pity be damned.
這是她自找的 你是清楚的
She's brought this upon herself, as well you know.
快走吧      不 我要跟她去
Now come.        No. I will go with her.
你哪裡也不許去
But you're not going anywhere.
我要跟她去 如果她願意的話
I will go with G, if G will have me,
無論你做什麼說什麼都阻止不了我們
and there's nothing you can do or say to stop either of us.
謝謝你來陪我     我不可以讓你單獨一人
Thank you for coming.        I couldn't not be with you.
該走了
It's time.
要不要讓...      不 我要自己去
Would it help...        No, I must take her.
夫人  我是格雷將軍
Your Grace, I'm General Grey.
查爾斯呢?
Where's Charles?
你丈夫說最好由我來處理這件事
Your husband thought it best if I took care of this.
格雷將軍
General Grey.
她的名字叫伊萊扎
Her name is Eliza.
走吧
Come on.
走吧  喬 都過去了 都過去了
Come on, G. I've got you. I've got you.
我不是很擅於表達自己
I'm not particularly adept at expressing myself
特別是在牽涉到個人情感時
when it comes to matters of a more personal nature.
但是我想試一下
But I shall try.
這幾年來 我的所作所為
Over the years, I have acted in ways
在你看來很無情
that you have judged to be harsh.
我不會讓你再受任何折磨了
Well, I do not wish for you to undergo any further suffering.
事實上 我希望我們能擁有平靜的生活
In fact, I would like our lives to find a calm normality.
梅爾本夫人安排了一次聚會
Lady Melbourne has arranged a small gathering
慶祝你度假歸來
in honor of your recent return from holiday.
基於這幾年來
And given some of the vague reports
流傳的一些流言蜚語
that have been circulating this past year
我覺得我們最好能出席
I think it would be wise for us to go.
也可以說是表現一下和睦
A show of unity, so to speak.
還有誰會去?
Who will be there?
所有人
Everybody.
如你所願吧
As you wish.
如此自由自在是多麼美好呀
How wonderful to be that free.
來啊 喬喬 來啊
Come here. Little G, come here.
德文郡公爵和公爵夫人
The Duke and Duchess of Devonshire
還有伊麗莎白·福斯特夫人
and Lady Elizabeth Foster.
夫人      見到你真高興
Your Grace.        It's lovely to see you.
歡迎回來 夫人
Welcome back, Your Grace.
失陪
Excuse me.
歡迎回來      歡迎回來 夫人
Welcome back.        Welcome home, Your Grace.
歡迎回來      歡迎回來 喬
Welcome back.        Welcome back, G.
大家一直都非常地想念您
Your presence has been sorely missed.
失陪一下
Would you excuse me?
格雷先生      夫人
Mr. Grey.        Your Grace.
我相信你們的旅程一定很愉快吧
I trust your tour was enjoyable.
是的
Yes.
我們在瑞士過的夏天 在尼斯過的冬天
We spent the summer in Switzerland and the winter in Nice.
讓我代表各位賓客
Well, I speak on behalf of everybody
對你的安全歸來表示由衷的高興
when I say how glad I am that you have arrived home safely.
你最近可好?
And what news with you?
我要訂婚了
I'm to be engaged.
跟潘森比小姐
To Lady Ponsonby.
很快就會向大家宣佈的
The announcement will follow shortly.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
我還有了一個侄女 叫伊萊扎
And I have a niece, Eliza,
我們都很寵愛她
who is very much loved.
改天你得來見見她
One day you should come and meet her,
不久以後
in a little while.
如果你願意的話
If you would like.
我非常願意
I would like that very much.
喬治亞娜重返社交界
繼續成為當代最富盛名
最具影響力的女人
查爾斯·格雷成為英國首相
喬治亞娜 貝絲還有公爵一直生活在一起
直到喬治亞娜去世
在喬治亞娜的祝福下
貝絲嫁給了公爵
成為下一任公爵夫人
看誰先抓到我
Who's going to catch me first?
我!      快 孩子們
Me!        Quick, girls.
快 我要跑掉啦
Quick, I'm going to get away!
快 孩子們 追上我
Come on, girls, keep running.
喬治亞娜經常秘密探訪伊萊扎
我愛你
And I love you.
伊萊扎將她的女兒命名為喬治亞娜